<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Chennai Nerd]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.chennainerd.in/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.chennainerd.in/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-31T21:32:46+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://www.chennainerd.in/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Chennai Nerd]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Want to automate things? Have a glance on Sikuli!]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.chennainerd.in/blog/2014/03/31/want-to-automate-things-have-a-glance-on-sikuli/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-31T15:14:47+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://www.chennainerd.in/blog/2014/03/31/want-to-automate-things-have-a-glance-on-sikuli</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You want to automate some repetitive tasks in daily usage of applications or
web pages, games or IT systems and networks etc., and you do not
have adequate tools in hand.</p>

<p>Then you are at the right place now. Just give a try for Sikuli, a simple tool
for GUI automation. Sikuli can automate any computer operations based on screen shots.</p>

<h2>Sikuli Installation steps</h2>

<h4>Step 1: Download the following from <a href="https://launchpad.net/sikuli/+download">https://launchpad.net/sikuli/+download</a></h4>

<pre><code>Sikuli-1.0.1-Supplemental-LinuxVisionProxy.zip (md5)
sikuli-setup.jar (md5)
</code></pre>

<h4>Step 2: Install dependencies</h4>

<p>Ubuntu users: Install the below packages (Dependencies for Sikuli)</p>

<pre><code>sudo apt-get install openjdk-7-jdk
sudo apt-get install libopencv-dev
sudo apt-get install libtesseract-dev
</code></pre>

<p>Unzip the .zip file and follow the readme steps to build a new <code>libvisionproxy.so</code> file.</p>

<p>Windows users: Install java jre 7</p>

<h4>Step 3: Install Sikuli using the jar file.</h4>

<p>Run the <code>Sikuli-setup.jar</code> by setting the executable bit if not set
on it and use the command:</p>

<pre><code>java -jar sikuli-setup.jar
</code></pre>

<p>Ubuntu users should replace the newly generated <code>libvisionproxy.so</code> with the
existing one in <code>&lt;Sikuli_installed_folder&gt;/libs/</code> location.</p>

<h4>Step 4: Launch the Sikuli IDE using the command.</h4>

<pre><code>cd &lt;Sikuli_installed_folder&gt;
runIDE.cmd (for windows users)
./runIDE (for Ubuntu users)
</code></pre>

<h4>Step 5: Run the Sikuli tests from command line using the command:</h4>

<pre><code>runIDE.cmd –r &lt;sikuli_test_name.sikuli&gt;    (for windows users)
./runIDE –r &lt;sikuli_test_name.sikuli&gt;      (for Ubuntu users)
</code></pre>

<h3>Sample Sikuli code snippet:</h3>

<p>Say you want to automate the following: launch a notepad, type some text and save it.</p>

<p>Below is the sample code written in Sikuli IDE.</p>

<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/qtvxGOA.png" alt="Sikuli" /></p>

<p>The same code snippet trying to open a diffent app say gedit, should work seamlessly in Ubuntu.
For web browser based automation, wait for my next blog on Selenium.</p>

<p>Happy automation folks !!!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I am a C programmer. Why i love AngularJS?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.chennainerd.in/blog/2014/02/22/i-am-a-c-programmer-why-i-love-angularjs/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-22T19:01:42+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://www.chennainerd.in/blog/2014/02/22/i-am-a-c-programmer-why-i-love-angularjs</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The intended audience for this blog are not the people who have profound knowledge in HTML and Javascript.  This is only for those who are in inertia to experiment with web development.  Also, please be aware that this is not beginner&rsquo;s tutorial for AngularJS.</p>

<p>I have this habit of trying some web related stuff rarely once in a year.  Couple of years back on a fine morning started to play with jQuery and was impressed by its power.  But at the end of the day thought there is so much to APIs to remember or at least be aware of. Then decided, it&rsquo;s not going to work out for me and that was the last time I tried anything on the web.</p>

<p>Last week I had a chance to play with AngularJS and my immediate reaction was &ldquo;WoW!!!&rdquo;. After my first encounter with AngularJS I thought this is not going to be just one day affair and fell in love with AngularJS. During the course of this blog I&rsquo;ll walk you through the features of AngularJS which impressed me.</p>

<h4>Framework and library:</h4>

<p>First of all, AngularJS is not library like jQuery, it is a framework.  So there is no onus of remembering the APIs.</p>

<h4>Empowering HTML:</h4>

<p>HTML was born when the intention of web was only to display static content.  As the name suggests that is only a markup language &ndash; nothing wrong, nobody to blame. The people who designed that had only scoped for that.  But now, the web is not that simple.
And being a C programmer I wished if there is anyway to add if condition, loop, block scope in HTML.  AngularJS comes as a prosthetic limb for the handicapped HTML.</p>

<p>To display an element only when a condition is met (i.e.,) having a if construct. This is possible in AngularJS using <code>ng-if</code> or <code>ng-show</code> directive.</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>&lt;input type="text" ng-model="customer.name" ng-if="customer.edit"&gt;
</span><span class='line'>&lt;span ng-bind="customer.name" ng-if="!customer.edit"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>If customer.edit is set true, customer.name will be displayed in text box, else will be displayed in span.</p>

<p>To iterate through a array of items and create a <code>&lt;ul&gt;</code> or <code>&lt;li&gt;</code> or even populate a
<code>&lt;table&gt;</code>.  <code>ng-repeat</code> directive does the job.</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
<span class='line-number'>13</span>
<span class='line-number'>14</span>
<span class='line-number'>15</span>
<span class='line-number'>16</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>&lt;table&gt;
</span><span class='line'>    &lt;thead&gt;
</span><span class='line'>        &lt;tr&gt;
</span><span class='line'>            &lt;th&gt;Name&lt;/th&gt;
</span><span class='line'>            &lt;th&gt;Amount&lt;/th&gt;
</span><span class='line'>            &lt;th&gt;ROI&lt;/th&gt;
</span><span class='line'>        &lt;/tr&gt;
</span><span class='line'>    &lt;/thead&gt;
</span><span class='line'>    &lt;tbody&gt;
</span><span class='line'>        &lt;tr ng-repeat="customer in customers"&gt;
</span><span class='line'>            &lt;td ng-bind="customer.name"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
</span><span class='line'>            &lt;td ng-bind="customer.amount"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
</span><span class='line'>            &lt;td ng-bind="customer.roi"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
</span><span class='line'>        &lt;/tr&gt;
</span><span class='line'>    &lt;/tbody&gt;
</span><span class='line'>&lt;/table&gt;</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>To restrict the scope of variables and functions within a block, <code>ng-controller</code> can be used.
Though the use of <code>ng-controller</code> is more than that.</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>&lt;script&gt;
</span><span class='line'>    angular.module("bank", []).
</span><span class='line'>    controller('BankController',
</span><span class='line'>        function BankController($scope) {
</span><span class='line'>            $scope.customers = [name:'kansamy', amount:'1000', roi:'9', edit:0}, {name:'munsamy', amount:'300', roi:'2', edit:0}];
</span><span class='line'>            $scope.customer = {name:'', amount:'', roi:'', edit:0};
</span><span class='line'>        });
</span><span class='line'>&lt;script&gt;
</span><span class='line'>&lt;body ng-app="bank" ng-controller="BankController"&gt;
</span><span class='line'>...
</span><span class='line'>&lt;/body&gt;</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>The scope of bank controller is throughout the <code>&lt;body&gt;</code>.
This scope can be restricted to any <code>&lt;div&gt;</code> or any other element by setting
<code>ng-controller</code> accordingly. <code>$scope</code> variable has a special meaning mapping to
the scope of the controller.</p>

<p>There is much more talk to about AngularJS &ndash; what I have captured here is only the picture of love at first sight.</p>

<p>I have hosted a simple no use application exercising these features of AngularJS
<a href="https://brilliant-fire-1717.firebaseapp.com/bank.html">https://brilliant-fire-1717.firebaseapp.com/bank.html</a></p>

<p>No wonder, these features can one day become integral part of HTML.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Best Places to learn programming]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.chennainerd.in/blog/2014/02/22/best-places-to-learn-programming/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-22T17:09:55+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://www.chennainerd.in/blog/2014/02/22/best-places-to-learn-programming</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Everyday, we hear news of acquisition of tech companies for million or billion dollars.
It creates a lot of excitement among programmers and even non programmers.
So everybody wanted to learn programming and even programmer from C, Java background
wanted to learn iOS, Android app development. Big question: Should i need
to go college to learn programming? Not anymore, we have lot of online companies
offering courses to train you like Ninja. Following are few places where you can learn to code.</p>

<h3><a href="http://codeschool.com/">Code School</a></h3>

<p><a href="http://codeschool.com/">Code School</a> teaches web technologies in the comfort of
your browser with video lessons, coding challenges, and screencasts. From my experience,
it is one of best places to learn web and mobile application development.
It costs <code>$29</code> per month. But it worths it.</p>

<h3><a href="http://www.codecademy.com/">Codecademy</a></h3>

<p>At Codecademy, you can learn to code in JavaScript, HTML and CSS, Python and Ruby.
Codecademy is <code>Free</code>. It is one of the most famous website to teach you to code interactively,</p>

<h3><a href="https://teamtreehouse.com/">Treehouse</a></h3>

<p>Treehouse can prepare you for a developer gig, even if you’ve got no experience.
A helpful iPad app also makes it easy to learn on the go.  Treehouse courses
are more project-oriented than language-oriented, so they are perfect for novice
programmer with a planned purpose, such as building a website, or an application.</p>

<p>It has two pricing plan. 1. <code>Basic($25)</code>  2. <code>Pro($49)</code> per month</p>

<h3><a href="https://www.udacity.com/">Udacity</a></h3>

<p>Udacity aims to bring college courses online specially Computer courses.
Udacity claims that online courses are rigorous and may even make you sweat.
Tackling projects built by tech leaders like Google, AT&amp;T, and Intuit,
you’ll stretch yourself and learn new and relevant skills.</p>

<h3><a href="https://www.learnstreet.com/">LearnStreet</a></h3>

<p>If you are that kind of personnel who do not fancy playful design and prefer to
deal with cold hard codes, LearnStreet is probably your thing. It currently offers
JavaScript, Python and Ruby courses at beginner level.</p>

<h3><a href="http://www.codehs.com/">codehs</a></h3>

<p>At this point all websites you read here are mainly dedicated to web development
and computer science, but CodeHS is one with simple and fun game programming lessons
that involve problem solving, JavaScript, animation, data structures,
game design and puzzle challenges.</p>

<h3><a href="https://www.coursera.org/">Coursera</a></h3>

<p>Coursera aims to bring college courses online — but it’s specifically focused
on making the “best” courses available. Here you’ll find a wealth of computer
science courses from schools not participating in the OCW program.</p>

<h3><a href="http://www.khanacademy.org/cs">khanacademy</a></h3>

<p>One of best known learning platform Khan Academy offers variety of courses, not only
computer science. It serves as an open playground for both novice and amateurs
particularly interested in learning drawing, animation and user interaction with code.</p>

<p>Be ready to code next Facebook.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tips for fasten your workflow in terminal]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.chennainerd.in/blog/2014/02/18/tips-for-faster-workflow-in-terminal/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-18T18:00:13+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://www.chennainerd.in/blog/2014/02/18/tips-for-faster-workflow-in-terminal</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Without a doubt and question, Terminal is home for all programmers.
It always wonderful to have shortcuts to save our precious seconds.
Here we will discuss about techniques to fasten your workflow.
Place all <code>bash</code> function and aliases inside your <code>.bash_profile</code> or <code>.bashrc</code>.</p>

<h3>Create and Change Directory</h3>

<p>Generally, we create a folder and then <code>cd</code> to created directory.
We can do it by</p>

<pre><code>take ()
{
    mkdir -p $1 &amp;&amp; cd $1
}
</code></pre>

<p>Type <code>take foobar</code> will create and change directory to <code>foobar</code></p>

<h3>Run static server</h3>

<p>If you are a web developer, you wanted to view static files in browser.
Run your static server by</p>

<pre><code>server ()
{
    local port="${1:-8000}";
    open "http://localhost:${port}/";
    python -c 'import SimpleHTTPServer;
    map = SimpleHTTPServer.SimpleHTTPRequestHandler.extensions_map;
    map[""] = "text/plain";
    for key, value in map.items():
        map[key] = value + ";charset=UTF-8";
    SimpleHTTPServer.test();' "$port"
}
</code></pre>

<p>Type <code>server</code> insider any directory and visit <code>http://localhost:8000/</code> in browser</p>

<h3>Git aliases</h3>

<p>If you are a git user, following aliases will save your time a lot.</p>

<pre><code>alias gcl='git clone'
alias ga='git add .'
alias gall='git add -A'
alias gst='git status'
alias gc='git commit -v'
alias gco='git checkout'
alias gl='git pull'
alias gp='git push'
alias gpo='git push origin'
</code></pre>

<h3>Run previous command</h3>

<p><code>!!</code> represents the previous command. Most of the time, we forgot to type sudo for
some command.</p>

<pre><code>sudo !!
</code></pre>

<p>Above will run the previous command with <code>sudo</code>. CAUTION: Your previous command MUST NOT BE
 <code>rm -rf /</code> :).</p>

<h3>Go back to old directory</h3>

<p>Sometimes we want to change directory to previous working directory which we changed from. And revert to previous working directory we can use same command. This is vary much useful cd command.</p>

<pre><code>cd -
</code></pre>

<p>We know, there are lot of cool tips out there. Share with us what you got.
Happy hacking.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
